 <TestItem CLASS="ssmc" METHOD="list">
 <Stem>
 <Paragraph>
   <Sentence>Katie is a biochemist. During her last trip to the Amazon 
	rainforest, she brought back some leaves from an exotic plant.
	The substance she extracted from the leaves has some
	 amazing properties: one drop on a given cell causes it to 
	 grow and divide, so that it generates an additional cell of the same size, 
	 along with a smaller bonus cell. That is, at the first division, 
	 there are three cells, made up of two large cells and one small cell.  
	 At the next division, the number of large cells and small cells doubles, so there 
	 are a total of six cells (4 large and 2 small cells) at the second division. 
	 The same pattern continues: as a result of each division, the number of large cells doubles; 
	 the number of small cells also doubles, so there are always half as many small cells as large cells.
   </Sentence>
 </Paragraph>
 <Paragraph>
  <Sentence>Your task is to find the expression for the number of 
  total cells present as a result of the <italics>n</italics>th division.  </Sentence> 
  </Paragraph>
  </Stem>
 <Distractor_list>
 <Distractor><Paragraph><Sentence> 3 * 2<sup><italics>n</italics>-1</sup></Sentence></Paragraph></Distractor>
  <Distractor><Paragraph><Sentence>2 * 3<sup><italics>n</italics>-1</sup></Sentence></Paragraph></Distractor>
  <Distractor><Paragraph><Sentence>3<sup><italics>n</italics></sup></Sentence></Paragraph></Distractor>
  <Distractor><Paragraph><Sentence>2<sup><italics>n</italics></sup></Sentence></Paragraph></Distractor>
  </Distractor_list>
 <key TYPE="SSMC">
 <response  SCORE="1" EVIDENCEVAL="1">
    <observable>1</observable> 
    <feedback TYPE="Student">Correct, good job!</feedback>
    <feedback TYPE="Teacher">The student has successfully modeled a real world problem by finding an explicit formula for a geometric sequence.</feedback>
  </response>
<response  SCORE="0" EVIDENCEVAL="0">
    <observable>2</observable>
        <feedback TYPE="Student">Sorry, that's not right.
 Try plugging in some numbers into the formula you chose, starting with the first 
 division: <italics>n</italics> = 1. 
 Then 2 * 3<sup><italics>n</italics>-1</sup> = 2 * 3<sup>0</sup> = 2 * 1 = 2. 
 But we know there are three cells, not two, after the first division, so your answer is not right. 
 The geometric sequence in this case is: 3, 6, 12, 24... for each division. The correct answer is: 
 3 * 2<sup><italics>n</italics>-1</sup>.</feedback>
        <feedback TYPE="Teacher">The student may have memorized the formula for a geometric sequence, and confused some of the terms.</feedback>
   </response>
<response  SCORE="0" EVIDENCEVAL="0">
    <observable>3</observable>
        <feedback TYPE="Student">Sorry, that's not right.
Try plugging in some numbers. Suppose <italics>n</italics> = 2. 
Then 3<sup><italics>n</italics></sup> =  3<sup><italics>2</italics></sup> = 9. 
But we know that there are six cells, not nine, after the second division. The geometric sequence in 
this case is: 3, 6, 12, 24... for each division. The correct answer is: 
 3 * 2<sup><italics>n</italics>-1</sup>.</feedback>
        <feedback TYPE="Teacher">In finding the formula, the student may have only looked at the number of cells following the first division, and may not have verified the pattern.</feedback>
   </response>
<response  SCORE="0" EVIDENCEVAL="0">
    <observable>4</observable>
        <feedback TYPE="Student">Sorry, that's not right. But you are close. You did find the correct 
        formula for the number of <emphasis>large cells</emphasis> as a result of the <italics>n</italics>th 
        division. Try plugging in some numbers. Suppose <italics>n</italics> = 1. 
        Then 2<sup><italics>n</italics></sup> =  2<sup><italics>1</italics></sup> = 2. 
        But we know that there are three cells, not two, after the first division. 
        The geometric sequence in this case is: 3, 6, 12, 24.... for each division. The correct answer is: 
 3 * 2<sup><italics>n</italics>-1</sup>.</feedback>
        <feedback TYPE="Teacher">The student may have observed that the number of large cells and small cells both double, and may have inferred that a power of two was involved. In fact this is the correct formula for the number of large cells.</feedback>
   </response>
  </key>
 <Metadata>
 <AeL ItemNode="tVerbalRuleExplicitModelGeometric3a" Difficulty="3">
  <PMNode LINK="true">VerbalRuleGeometric</PMNode> 
  <PMNode LINK="true">ExplicitGeometric</PMNode> 
	<PMNode>ModelGeometric</PMNode> 
  
  </AeL>
  </Metadata>
  </TestItem>